A Guide to the Virginia Municipal League Archives 1925-1989
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Virginia Municipal League Archives 1925-1989
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 276
92.3 linear feet
Virginia Municipal League
Administrative Information
Access
Any financial or personnel materials still in the collection are not available for research.
Acquisition Information
The Executive Director of the Virginia Municipal League donated the materials to Special Collections and Archives in 1992.
Biographical/Historical Information
Was League of Virginia Municipalities.
Scope and Content Information
This collection contains papers held by the VML. These papers deal with the issues that any municipality would be concerned with. A few examples are public safety, waste water regulations, annexation issues, drug dependency and programs, etc. The main bulk seems to be information dealing with Virginia municipalities complying to federal and state regulations. The collection includes reports, bulletins, publications and legal documents. In addition, the library also receives the VML publication, Town and County; for more up-to-date information.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged by subject and chronological therein.
Contents List
- Bulletins 1-19 July 1933-April 1937 (Box 1)
- Reports 1-27 May 1925-December 1929 (Box 1)
- Reports 26-50 December 1929-March 1931 (Box 1)
- Reports 51-75 March 1931-July 1931 (Box 1)
- Reports 76-100 August 1931-July 1932 (Box 1)
- Reports 102-124 September 1932-March 1933 (Box 1)
- Reports 127-150 May 1933-October 1934 (Box 1)
- Reports 151-175 November 1934-July 1935 (Box 1)
- Convention Transcript 1973-1977 (Box 2)
- Publications: Legislative Bulletins (Box 3)
  1926, 1928, 1930, 1932-1934, 1936, 1938, 1940, 1942, 1945-1948, 1950, 1952, 1954,
- Reports 332-470 January 1951-April 1965 (Box 4)
- Reports 176-331 May 1935-January 1951 (Box 5)
- Reports 471-545 May 1965-August 1974 (Box 6)
- Reports 546-562 (Box 6)
- Reports 563-579 (Box 6)
- Correspondence (Box 7)
- Virginia Municipal Review Magazine Issues 1963-1976 (Box 7)
- Exhibitor Correspondence (Box 7)
- Executive Committee 1975 (Box 7)
- Potential Members 1975 (Box 7)
- Executive Committee 1973-1976 (Box 7)
- Executive Committee Goals 1977 (Box 7)
- Executive Committee January 1977 (Box 7)
- Executive Committee July 1977 (Box 7)
- Executive Committee July 1976 (Box 7)
- Executive Committee September 1976 (Box 7)
- Convention 1977 (Box 7)
- Publications: Legislative Bulletins 1955-1959 (Box 8)
- Convention Proceedings, Transcript 1967-1972 (Box 9)
- Statement of Special Committee on Finance 1965 (Box 10)
- Statement of Special Committee on Annexation 1963 (Box 10)
- Statement of Special Committee on Taxation 1962 (Box 10)
- Statement of Municipal Electric Power Association 1962 (Box 10)
- Statement of Street and Highway Committee 1962 (Box 10)
- Prelim. VML Policy Statement and Legislative Program 1984 (Box 10)
- VML Policy Statement and Legislative Program (Box 10)
- Prelim. VML Policy Statement and Legislative Program 1985 (Box 10)
- Comprehensive Conflict of Interests Act: A Reference Manual Basic Risk Management 1983 (Box 10)
- Handbook by Phyllis Sherman 1983 (Box 10)
- Giving Technical Assistance 1980 (Box 10)
- Legislation Affecting Local Government 1978 (Box 10)
- Local Financial Concerns 1976, 2 vols. (Box 10)
- Virginia Local Legislator (a Guide...) 1972 (Box 10)
- Statewide Salaries and Personnel Practices 1975 (Box 10)
- Statewide Salaries and Personnel Practices 1976 (Box 10)
- Report on Legislation 1976 (Box 10)
- Statewide Salaries and Personnel Practices 1976 (Box 10)
- Statewide Salary Survey 1977 (Box 10)
- Report on Legislation 1977 (Box 10)
- Statewide Salary Survey 1978 (Box 10)
- Shall a Town Become a City of the Second Class 1951 (Box 10)
- Statement of the Sub-Committee on Municipal Taxation 1956 (Box 10)
- Group Purchasing Service December 1, 1936 (Box 10)
- Rept. of Third Va. Police Instructors' Training School 11/12/34 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Virginia Cities by Chester W. Bain (Jt. Rept. 4) 1950 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Virginia Cities by Chester W. Bain (Jt. Rept. 5) 1952 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Va. Cities by Walter Stoneham (Jt. Rept. 11) 1958 (Box 10)
- Municipal License Tax Manual by James O'Neal (Jt. Rept. 13) 1959 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Va. Cities by Walter Stoneham (Jt. Repts. 14-15) 1959-1960 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Va. Cities by William Griffin (Jt. Repts. 16-17) 1961-1962 (Box 10)
- An Index of Virginia City Charters (Jt. Rept. 12) 1959 (Box 10)
- Practices Followed in Providing Fire Services to Adjoining Jurisdictions 1955 (Box 10)
- Extension of Services to Subdivisions and Areas Both Withing and Without the Corporate Limits of Virginia Towns August 1955 (Box 10)
- Some Observations on Taxation in Virginia Cities with Special Emphasis on the Burden of Real Estate Taxes December 1939 (Box 10)
- Statement of Committee on Consolidation of Local Governments of the League of Virginia Municipalities May 1959 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Va. Cities: (by Bruce Ransom, Jt. Rept.38) 1978 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Va. Cities (by Albert Spengler, Jt. Repts. 39-40) 1981 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Virginia Counties (by Bruce Ransom) 1977 (Box 10)
- Legislation Affecting Local Government (Report 577) 1983 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Va. Cities by Mark S. Fleming (Jt. Rept. 30) 1972 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Va. Cities: by Paul K. Cases (Jt. Rept. 32) 1974 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Va. Cities: by Janie E. Bowen (Jt. Repts. 33-34) 1975-1976 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Va. Cities: by Bruce Ransom (Jt. Repts. 35, 37) 1977-1978 (Box 10)
- Drafting a Va. Municipal Charter by J. Weeks (Jt. Rept. 18) 1963 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Va. Cities by William Griffin (Jt. Rept. 19) 1963 (Box 10)
- General Accounting and Fiscal Reporting Practices in Virginia Cities, by Milton L. McPherson 1950 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Virginia's Cities: by Albert W. Spengler 1982 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Va. Cities by Paul K. Casey (Jt. Rept. 29) 1971 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Virginia's Cities: by Albert W. Spengler 1983 (Box 10)
- Handbook for Va. Mayors and Councilmen by Weeks (Jt. Rept. 20) 1963 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Va. Cities by Stanley I. Goldman (Jt. Repts. 21-22) 1964-1965 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Va. Cities by Robert J. Austin (Jt. Repts. 23-24) 1966-1967 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Va. Cities by Donald C. Dixon (Jt. Rept. 26) 1969 (Box 10)
- An Index of Virginia City Charters (Joint Report no. 27) 1970 (Box 10)
- Tax Rates in Va. Cities by Donald C. Dixon (Jt. Rept. 28) 1970 (Box 10)
- Convention Proceedings 1937-1954 (Box 11)
- Convention Proceedings 1955-1964 (Box 12)
- Convention 1960-1967 (Box 13)
- Executive Director: Notices; Information Requests 1955-1959, 1961-1965 (Box 14)
- Executive Director: Notices; Information Requests 1966-1967, 1971-1974, 1976-1977, 1979 (Box 15)
- Arson Bill (Box 16)
- Street-Use Regulations (27-13) (Box 16)
- Legal Opinions (20-4) (Box 16)
- Legal Opinions (Adamson) (L-2.1) 1960-1964, 1967 (Box 16)
- Legal Opinions (Dobbins) 1970-1975 (Box 16)
- Legal Opinions 1970-1980 (Box 16)
- executive Committee Minutes (V-4.711) 1935-1959 (Box 17)
- Permanent Correspondence 1930-1959 (Box 17)
- Minutes of the Executive Va. Weights and Measures Association Weights Convention (V. 4.8) 1935-1941, 1947-1959 (Box 17)
- Weights Convention Proceedings (V 4.81) 1939-1943, 1946, 1948, 1953-1954 (Box 17)
- Building Convention 1941-1959 (Box 18)
- Building Convention Proceedings 1943-1944 (Box 18)
- State Wide Building Code Committee 1938 (Box 18)
- Virginia Building Officials Assoc. Newsletter (Box 18)
- Building Convention 1960-1970 (Box 18)
- Virginia Building Officials Association: Other Committees (Box 18)
- VBOA Information (Box 18)
- VBOA: Mid-year meeting 1980 (Box 18)
- VBOA: Charter Chapter Proposal (Box 18)
- VBOA: Conference Evaluation 1979 (Box 18)
- VBOA: Legislative File 1979 (Box 18)
- VBCOA: Regional Training Seminars with Dept. of Housing (Box 18)
- Correspondence 1929-1939 (Box 18)
- Correspondence 1960- (Box 18)
- League Convention: Richmond 1972 (Box 18)
- Convention Proceedings-Transcripts 1934-1936 (Box 19)
- Convention-Exhibits 1961 (Box 19)
- Convention-Proceedings-Transcript 1965-1966 (Box 19)
- Seal 1963 (Box 19)
- Executive Director: Notices, Information Requests 1978 (Box 19)
- City/Town Financial Reports-Worksheets (Box 19)
- League Convention, Roanoke, Va 1968 (Box 20)
- League Convention Groups 1968 (Box 20)
- League Convention Group Meetings 1969 (Box 20)
- League Convention 1970 (Box 20)
- League Convention, Virginia Beach, Va 1971 (Box 20)
- League Convention, Norfolk, Va 1973 (Box 20)
- Executive Committee Meetings November 1977 (Box 20)
- President's Convention Notebook 1977 (Box 20)
- Executive Committee 1977 (Box 20)
- Executive Committee Minutes 1970-1979 (Box 20)
- Social Services Funding Formula (Box 21)
- Workfare (Box 21)
- SFCAV 1980-1981 (Box 21)
- SFCAV 1982 (Box 21)
- Mental Health-Mental Retardation Report 1980 (Box 21)
- Long-Term Care (Box 21)
- Human Services (Box 21)
- Governor Davis' Task Force (Box 21)
- Budget (Box 21)
- General Assembly (Box 21)
- Social Services Issues 1982 (Box 21)
- Office Lease 1935-1975 (Box 21)
- Salary Scales 1964-1972 (Box 21)
- Manager's Convention, Fredericksburg, Va 1969 (Box 22)
- Manager's Convention, Hot Springs, Va 1973 (Box 22)
- Manager's Convention, Business Meeting Proceedings 1974 (Box 22)
- Manager's Business Proceedings 1975 (Box 22)
- Business Meeting Proceedings 1973- (Box 22)
- Convention Minutes 1955 (Box 22)
- Conventions (Box 22)
- Statistics on Police Administration in Va. May, 1943 (Box 23)
- Indirect Cost Allocation Plan August 25, 1977 (Box 23)
- Work Plan Fiscal Yr. (Mid Atlantic Federal Regional Council) 1975 (Box 23)
- Federal Regional Council Conference (Box 23)
- Virginia State Liaison Team (Box 23)
- Government/VA. (Box 23)
- General Assembly 1975 (Box 23)
- Executive Order No. 20 Establishing GMPC and GMSC (Box 23)
- NLC-Human Resources Task Force (Box 23)
- NLC Manpower Reports--Memorandums (Box 23)
- NLC Washington Report and NLC Action Call (Box 23)
- Planning Districts (Box 23)
- Revenue Sharing (Box 23)
- Advisory Committee Social Service Plan (Box 23)
- Title XX Local Comments (Box 23)
- Title 20: X Copies (Box 23)
- Transportation (Box 23)
- Welfare--General Relief (Box 23)
- General Relief Draft-Cost Study (Box 23)
- Minority Report-General Relief (Box 23)
- Health System Agencies (HSA's) (Box 23)
- HEW--Capacity Building (Box 23)
- Housing and Community Development Workshop (Box 23)
- VML Human Resources Project-Orientation (Box 23)
- VML Human Resources Committee-Policy (Box 23)
- Weights Convention (V 4.8) 1942-1946 (Box 24)
- Fire Convention (V 6.8) 1953-1961 (Box 25)
- Fire Convention Proceedings 1949-1961 (Box 25)
- Power Convention: Fall and Spring 1954-1957 (Box 26)
- Power Convention: (V 7.8) 1958-1967 (Box 26)
- Photographs (Box 27-28)
- Councilman's Institute (LGOC) (V 9.3) 1964 (Box 29)
- Councilman's Institute (LGOC) (V 9.3) 1966 (Box 29)
- Labor-Management Training Session (V 9.12) (Box 29)
- Organization and Administration of Water Bureau (W 1.1) (Box 29)
- Water Franchises, Cooperatives and Contracts (W 1.12) (Box 29)
- Historical M.E.P.A.V. Minutes (Box 29)
- VEPCO Municipals (Box 29)
- Municipal Electric Power Association 1983 (Box 29)
- M.E.P.A. Federal Energy Regulation Commission 1983 (Box 29)
- M.E.P.A. Meeting Minutes, Correspondence 1981-1982 (Box 29)
- Beck Contracts (Box 29)
- R.F.P. Contracts (Box 29)
- M.E.P.A.V. Conference 1982 (Box 29)
- Financial Report Quarterly (Forms 315 and 315a) (Box 30)
- Advertising-Virginia Town and City (Box 30)
- Advertising Rates-Other Publications (Box 30)
- Police Chiefs' Convention 1976 (Box 30)
- OEO Project Annual Audit (Box 30)
- Budget--VML Grant (Box 30)
- HRD (R.L. DeCair) (Box 30)
- Photographs (Primarily of Conventions) (Box 31)
- Convention 1924-1959 (Box 32)
- Power Supply Study 1980 (Box 33)
- M.E.P.A.V. Circulars 1979- (Box 33)
- Power Conference 1976-1979 (Box 33)
- Power Conference 1969-1974 (Box 33)
- Correspondence 1953-1960 (Box 33)
- Resolutions 1960-1969 (Box 33)
- Resolutions, Prior (V 7.3) 1960 (Box 33)
- Secretary's Reports (V 7.5) 1960-1979 (Box 33)
- Secretary's Reports Prior to 1960 (V 7.5) (Box 33)
- Municipal Electric Power General (Box 33)
- Circular Letters (V 7.6) (Box 33)
- Executive Committee Minutes (V 7.711) (Box 33)
- Power Convention (V 7.8) 1968-1974 (Box 33)
- Executive Committee (V 7.71) (Box 33)
- Applications for Essays for the VML Achievement Award (Box 34)
- Handbook for Trial of Street and Sidewalk Injury Cases in Virginia by James Eichner September 1961 (Box 34)
- City Files Alphabetically, A (Alexandria) through L (Lynchburg) (Box 35)
- City Files Alphabetically, M (McKenney) through P (Purceville) (Box 36)
- City Files Alphabetical, Q (Quantico) through Y (Yorktown) (Box 37)
- Resolutions (V.3.3) 1933-1979 (Box 38)
- Secretary's Reports 1930-1979 (Box 38)
- Circular Letters 1930- (Box 38)
- VBOA Conference 1976-1979 (Box 38)
- Budget and Finance (Box 38)
- Executive Committee (V 3.71) (Box 38)
- Executive Committee Minutes (V 3.711) (Box 38)
- Committees (Box 38)
- VBOA Exhibits (Box 38)
- Building Convention 1971-1975 (Box 38)
- Other Committees (V 5.73) 1968 (Box 39)
- Managers 1974-1975 (Box 39)
- HR Project--Interoffice and Outside Correspondence, Reports of Staff Visits (Box 39)
- HR Project-Miscellaneous Publications (Box 39)
- Statement of Committee on Consolidation of Local Government of the VML to the Virginia Advisory Legislative Council May 1959 (Box 39)
- Index of Virginia City Charters (Joint Report #12 revision) 1960 (Box 39)
- Handbook for Virginia Mayors and Council Members (Box 39)
- Refuse Collection Rates--Cities, Counties and Urban Counties 1979 (Box 39)
- March Analysis: Annexation Legislation 1979 (Box 39)
- Legislation Affecting Local Government 1979 (Box 39)
- Legislative and Staff Work Program 1980 (Box 39)
- On Call Survey for Foremen and Laborers (Box 39)
- Municipal Policy Statement 1980 (Box 39)
- Overview of Local Option 12/10/80 (Box 39)
- Summary of Judicial Review of Local Land Use Decisions in Virginia (Box 39)
- Virginia Association of Counties-Historical Information (Box 39)
- Statement of Executive Committee of VML to Metropolitan Areas Study Committee June 1967 (Box 39)
- Survey of State and Local General Sales Tax (Rep. #473) 10/65 (Box 39)
- Mervis Uniforms (Portsmouth, Va) (Box 39)
- Sterling Park Development Corporation (Sterling, VA) (Box 39)
- Noland Company (Richmond, VA) (Box 39)
- Lone Star Industries (Norfolk, Va) (Box 39)
- Luck Quarries (Richmond, Va) (Box 39)
- Kenbridge Construction Company (Kenbridge, Va) (Box 39)
- H and S Construction Company (Roanoke, VA) (Box 39)
- Friend Sand and Gravel Company, Inc. (Petersburg,VA) (Box 39)
- DeLuca Construction Corporation (Falls Church, VA) (Box 39)
- W. Boyce Blanchard (Newport News, Va) (Box 39)
- Refuse Collection and Disposal Practices in VA Cities and Urban Counties (unpublished report) April 1975 (Box 39)
- League Statement to VALC on Highways November 1964 (Box 39)
- General Correspondence to Members and Relevant Legislative Updates 1950-1970 (Box 40)
- General Incoming Correspondence (Box 41)
- Fairfax County (Box 41)
- Perceptions of Innovation Under CETA (Box 41)
- Human Resources Section-DSPCA (Box 41)
- League of California Cities (Box 41)
- HRD-Brochures (Box 41)
- Community Development Officials (Box 41)
- VML/HRD Proposal (Box 41)
- Application Forms-Resume (Box 41)
- Results of VML/HRD Survey 1975 (Box 41)
- Community Profile-Charlottesville, Va (Box 41)
- Human Resources Assembly Feedback and Evaluation (Box 41)
- HRD--Charlottesville, Va (Box 41)
- Child Care Task Force (Box 41)
- Department of Community Development (Box 41)
- HRA-Consultants Proposals (Box 41)
- HRA-Consultants Report (Box 41)
- VML Human Resources Proposal (Box 41)
- HRD Publication (Box 41)
- Audit (Box 41)
- OEO/CSA Legislation Budget (Box 41)
- Ohio Municipal League (Box 41)
- National League of Cities (Box 41)
- National Municipal League Policy (Box 41)
- OEO Bank Statements Cancelled Checks (Box 41)
- OEO Correspondence (Box 41)
- Survey and Audit Compliance (Box 41)
- Financial Reporting Requirements (Box 41)
- News Release (Box 41)
- Correspondence-Suffolk (Box 41)
- Insurance--Bonding (Box 41)
- Correspondence A-Z (Box 41)
- Long Distance Phone Call Forms (Box 41)
- Manual of Operations for the Social Development Commission and Related Task Forces (City of Charlottesville) June 1974 (Box 41)
- OEO Project (Box 41)
- OEO Bills Paid 1975 (Box 41)
- Suffolk Grant Information (Box 41)
- Budget (Box 41)
- OEO Checks--Statements 1975 (Box 41)
- HRD Project-VML: R.L. DeCair, Executive Director (Box 41)
- VML HR Project (Box 42)
- HR Project (Box 42)
- Human Services Planning, Financing and Delivery in VA (3 vols.) (Box 42)
- Gail Whitlow's VML Packet (Box 42)
- CSA Charlottesville Evaluation (Box 42)
- Miscellaneous (Box 42)
- HRD Project-Funds and Assistance (Box 42)
- HR Programs-State League (Box 42)
- HR Survey (Box 42)
- VML/HRD Proposal (Box 42)
- Federal Bulletin (Box 42)
- Insurance Policies (Box 42)
- OEO Income 1974 (Box 42)
- Job Specifications (OEO) (Box 42)
- VML/HRD Proposal (Box 42)
- Personnel Data (Box 42)
- Leave Policy--Personnel Policy (Box 42)
- Grant Information ($20,000) (Box 42)
- Charlottesville Budget (Box 42)
- Correspondence-Charlottesville (Box 42)
- Quarterly Reports (Box 42)
- Monthly Financial Statements (Box 42)
- OEO Bills Paid 1974 (Box 42)
- OEO-A.M. Pullen Audit Report (Box 42)
- Field Reports (Box 42)
- Field Report Forms (Box 42)
- Inventory Listings (HR) (Box 42)
- Meetings (Box 42)
- Memos to File (Box 42)
- Newsclippings (Box 42)
- Newsletter and Other Communication, National (Box 42)
- Applications for Funds and Assistance (Box 42)
- Committee on Human Resources (Box 42)
- NLC Correspondence (HR) re: Program Development (Box 42)
- Building Convention (V 3.9) 1930-1940 (Box 43)
- Building Convention Proceedings (V 3.91) 1930-1931 (Box 43)
- Councilmen's Institute (LGOC) (V 9.3) 1956-1962 (Box 43)
- Managers Institutes-Short Courses 1959-1960 (Box 43)
- Public Finance Officer's School (V 9.5) (Box 43)
- Weights and Measures School (V 9.6) (Box 43)
- Utility Operator's School (V 9.7) 1939-1943 (Box 43)
- Utility Operator's School 1939-1943 (Box 43)
- Water Works School 1936 (Box 43)
- Municipal Planning Institute (V 9.9) 1945 (Box 43)
- School for Building Inspectors (V 9.10) (Box 43)
- Institute of Public Affairs (UVA) (V 9.11) (Box 43)
- Fire Schools (V 9.2) (Box 43)
- Fire Convention (V 6.8) 1948-1952 (Box 44)
- Secretary's Reports Prior to 1960 (V 6.5) (Box 44)
- Executive Committee (V 6.71) 1948-1957 (Box 44)
- Executive Committee Minutes (V 6.711) 1948-1957 (Box 44)
- Fire Legislative Committee (V 6.74) 1961-1968 (Box 44)
- Fire Safety Committee (V 6.75) 1959-1960 (Box 44)
- Fire Training Committee (V 6.76) (Box 44)
- Fire Work Committee (V 6.77) 1961 (Box 44)
- Task Force Committee-Other Committees (V 1.772) (Box 44)
- Power Convention-General (V 7.8) (Box 44)
- I.P.A. (Box 45)
- Legislation (Box 45)
- Migrant Report (Box 45)
- Memos-Model Cities Association (NAHRO) (Box 45)
- Organization Development Consultants, Inc. (Box 45)
- CAA's (Box 45)
- Community Services Day (Box 45)
- Commission on Human Resources Priorities (Box 45)
- D.S.P.C.A/Human Resources (Box 45)
- Elderly/Aging (Box 45)
- Employee Bargaining (Box 45)
- American Airlines (Box 45)
- Falls Church (Box 45)
- Staunton (Box 45)
- Suffolk (Box 45)
- Affirmative Action (Box 45)
- A.S.P.A Public Administration-Graduate Opportunities (Box 45)
- Articles (Box 45)
- City Revenues Questionnaires (Report #439) December 1961 (Box 45)
- Dr. Kilpatrick's Work Sheets on City Revenues December 1961 (Box 45)
- Town Revenues Questionnaire (Report #440) December 1961 (Box 45)
- Annexation Information for Various Questionnaires.... (Box 45)
- Annexation Questionnaires 1962 (Box 45)
- Annexation Information-Cities-Questionnaires December 1960 (Box 45)
- Annexation Questionnaires November 1961 (Box 45)
- Annexation Information-Towns-Questionnaires December 1960 (Box 45)
- Councilmen's Institute-LGOC (V 9.3) 1968, 1970, 1972-1976 (Box 46)
- Fire Schools (V 9.2) 1933-1936 (Box 46)
- Managers-Old (V 5.71) (Box 47)
- Correspondence (V 5.1) 1948-1959 (Box 47)
- International City Management Association Conference 1981 (Box 47)
- Resolutions (V 5.3) (Box 47)
- Resolutions Prior to 1960 (V 6.3) (Box 47)
- Virginia I.C.M.A.-Circular Letters (V 5.6) (Box 47)
- Virginia I.C.M.A.-Executive Committee Minutes (V 5.711) (Box 47)
- Correspondence (V 6.1) 1958-1959 (Box 47)
- Correspondence (Permanent) (V 6.1) 1929-1949 (Box 47)
- Manager's Training Committee (V 5.72) (Box 47)
- Manager's Convention (V 5.8) 1945, 1948-1949, 1951-1968 (Box 47)
- Manager's Convention (V 5.8) 1970-1972, 1974 (Box 48)
- I.C.M.A. (Virginia Section) Convention 1975 (Box 48)
- Circular Letters 1966-1976 (Box 48)
- Secretary's Reports (V 5.5) (Box 48)
- Managers' Executive Committee Meeting (Box 48)
- I.C.M.A. (Virginia Section) General (V5) (Box 48)
- Executive Committee Minutes (V 5.71) (Box 48)
- Manager's Executive Committee (V 5.71) 1974-1975 (Box 48)
- Membership (V. 5.41) (Box 48)
- Resolutions (V 5.3) 1960- (Box 48)
- Constitution and By-Laws (V 5.2) (Box 48)
- Correspondence (V 5.1) 1960- (Box 48)
- Budget and Finance (V 5.4) (Box 48)
- Legislative Committee 1965-1969, 1973 (Box 49)
- LGOC 1977 (Box 50)
- Achievement Awards Program April 1979 (Box 50)
- Administration of Local Government 1971-1979 (Box 51)
- Administration and Organization 1971-1972 (Box 51)
- Adult Book Stores (N.D.) (Box 51)
- Agricultural and Forest Land Preservation 1975-1981 (Box 51)
- Air Quality Control 1970-1979 (Box 51)
- Ambulances and Rescue Squad 1970-1983 (Box 51)
- Annexation 1977-1979 (Box 51)
- Annexation Bill #603 1978-1979 (Box 51)
- Annexation 1974-1978 (Box 51)
- Annexation Court Cases 1963-1981 (Box 51)
- Annexation 1972-1986 (Box 52)
- Annexation Task Force 1978-1979 (Box 52)
- Virginia's Revised Annexation Policy 1979-1980 (Box 52)
- Asbestos 1978 (Box 52)
- Assessment Taxation and Collection 1974-1979 (Box 52)
- At Large Elections 1985-1989 (Box 52)
- Bank Stock Tax Suit 1978-1979 (Box 52)
- Bank Stock Tax 1979-1980 (Box 52)
- Bingo 1973-1979 (Box 52)
- Bonds and Referendums 1957-1984 (Box 52)
- Bottle Bill 1979-1981 (Box 52)
- Building Maintenance Codes 1988 (Box 52)
- Business, Professional and Occupational Licenses 1977-1984 (Box 52)
- Cable Television 1965-1983 (Box 53)
- Cable Television and Streetlighting 1972-1981 (Box 53)
- Cable Television 1970-1981 (Box 53)
- Cash Management 1980 (Box 53)
- Cash vs. Stauton 1978-1979 (Box 53)
- Cemetry Ownership 1961-1971 (Box 53)
- Certification of Craftsmen 1978 (Box 53)
- City-Council Intergovernmental Relationships 1974-1980 (Box 53)
- City and County Consolidation 1963-1981 (Box 53)
- City and Town Managers 1976-1983 (Box 53)
- Civil Rights 1964-1978 (Box 53)
- Coastal Zone Management 1979-1980 (Box 53)
- Commercial Aviation 1970-1979 (Box 53)
- Community Development 1978-1979 (Box 53)
- Community Growth 1979-1981 (Box 53)
- Community Public Relations 1969-1982 (Box 53)
- Conditional Zoning 1976-1980 (Box 54)
- Condominiums and Apartments 1973-1981 (Box 54)
- Conflicts of Interest 1982-1984 (Box 54)
- Congressional Delegation Papers 1981-1983 (Box 54)
- Constitutional Officers 1982 (Box 54)
- Count/City/Town Regulation Differences 1988 (Box 54)
- County Forms of Government (N.D.) (Box 54)
- Court Reports 1985-1989 (Box 54)
- Crime Prevention 1971-1975 (Box 54)
- Dam Safety 1980-1982 (Box 54)
- Desegregation 1966-1972 (Box 54)
- Digest Opinions of the VA Supreme Court 1986-1989 (Box 54)